A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Log Files (Grant and Project Proposals) FA734
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Log Files (Grant and Project Proposals)
1951-1995
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation
FA734
598 microform reels
Log Files (Grant Project Proposals) are housed on 598 reels of microfilm, numbered L-001 to L-598. The first 146 reels are 35mm microfilm, while the remaining 452 reels are 16mm microfilm.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Arrangement note
Log Files (Grant & Project Proposals) are identified by a unique Log File # in the Ford Foundation Archives. Log File #s are formatted similar to the Foundation's grant numbers (PA numbers).
Each Log File # begins with the letter "L", followed by the two-digit year, and a sequential number within that year. For example: L60-123 = Log File, 1960, #123
However, during the 1950s Log Files were sometimes numbered with only one digit for the year, for example: L5-123 = Log File, 1955, #123
Each Log File was recorded in a series of Log Books, hence the name 'Log Files'.
The Ford Foundation Archive includes Log Files dating from 1951 to 1995. Log Files were microfilmed by year, and numerically by Log File# within each year. However there are many exceptions, and generally Log Files from 1977 to 1995 were not microfilmed in numerical order.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Ford Foundation archive was deposited at RAC in 2011. Ford Foundation records, correspondence, reports, program files and officers papers were transferred to, and accessioned by, RAC beginning in 2011. Accessions continue as necessary.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be restricted from scholarly research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment.
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be restricted from scholarly research at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/RAC Head of Reference.
Other Finding Aids note
Log Files (Grant & Project Proposals) are indexed by the Ford Foundations Central Index cards, 1950-1996 (FA736). The Central Index cards provide Log File numbers only, not microfilm reel numbers.
The Ford Foundation's LINKS database (available only to RAC staff), from which the description for the 1977-1995 Log Files presented here originates, provides indexing to 1,811 Log Files from 1977-2002, although this is not a complete inventory of the Log Files from that period. 133 of the 1,811 documented Log Files dating from the 1990s-2002 are not contained in the collection at RAC.
Grant & Project Proposals (Log Files) from 1951 to 1981 are listed by Log File number in the Ford Foundation's Log Books.
Scope and Contents
Types of records include: grant and project log files.
- 1951
  - L51-1772 - Liquidation of Illiteracy in Latin America (Bernard Greensfelder), 1951 (Reel L-1)
  - L51-2406 - 'Vandenberg Foreign Policy Center', University of Michigan - Memorial to Arthur H. Vandenberg Jr. in the form of a foreign policy center - James K. Pollock, 1951 (Reel L-1)
  - L51-2469 - London House (Dominion Students' Hall Trust), 1951 (Reel L-1)
- 1952
  - L52-418 - United Nations, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-488 - International relations - Donald C. Stone, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-489 - Cooperatives and underdeveloped countries - Gordon H. Ward, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-2040 - Economic problems of Panama - John C. Wiley, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-2106 - Proposed Point IV project for aiding purchasers of Crown Lands in Iran - Paul V. Maris, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-2125 - Film on India and Asia - Julien Bryan, Douglas Ensminger, and Chester Bowles, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-2519 - Compilation and publication of detailed information regarding programs of foreign assistance in India - Douglas Ensminger, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-2726 - The Great Creators of Our Time, An Archive of Films, 1952 (Reel L-1)
  - L52-3031 - Colombo Plan - British Commonwealth (Richard E. Webb; Richard G. Casey), 1952 (Reel L-1, Reel L-2)
- 1953
  - L53-232 - Kiyosato Educational Expirement Project, Japan - Program of village development, booklet "Chronicle of an Idea" - Col. Paul Rusch, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-429 - Proposed seminar for American Propagandists Abroad, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-441 - Foreign Area Publications Fund - Intercultural Publications - Philip Moseley, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-554 - Foreign fellowship program (Sania Hamady), 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-753 - Monopoly in the Music Field - Ernest Bacon, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-926 - Support for Pilot Teacher Training Course in Conservation Education - California Federation of Women's Clubs - Camilla Anderson, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1140 - Exhange funds for tension areas outside countries with Ford Foundation programs, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1178 - Study school systems in politically controlled cities - John P. Milligan, Atlanta City Public Schools, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1316 - Establish a Vinland Institute - Henry Goddard Leach, American-Scandinavian Foundation, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1346 - Importance of Capital formation in India, and general comments on India - Robert Jackson, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1432 - "Still Plan" - Means for advancing solutions to all our major national and world problems - Jack Still, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1792 - Broad training program for training of village health educators in underdeveloped areas of the world - John Z. Bowers, University of Utah School of Medicine, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-1858 - European unity - Henry J. Kellerman, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2032 - Econ. Study Comm. on International Fiscal, Monetary, and Trade, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2060 - Analysis of Federal tax system, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2061 - TV program, "These are the facts" for Ford Foundation representatives, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2248 - Grant for Education in Ethiopia, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2477 - Publication of early Portuguese records on Africa (Central African Archvies, W. Hiller), 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2521 - Santa Clara County Youth Center, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2621 - Development of the South African Institute of International Affairs, and its library, 1953 (Reel L-2)
  - L53-2630: Grant for equipment for work in East Africa, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-2687: Capital formation in underdeveloped areas, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-2884: Projects in Germany, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-2895: Strengthening social sciences, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-2896: Research in Burma, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-2950: Support to Capricorn Africa Society, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-3052: Support for White House conference on peace conditions of the United Nations, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-3054: Evaluation of technical assistance activities in Burma, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-3090: Cultural exchange, France, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-3095: Better relations between nations of the world (International Relations), 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-3132: Assistance to non-governmental organizations in India, Douglas Ensminger, 1953 (Reel L-3)
  - L53-3214: Possible cooperation between Ford Foundation and CAPES (National Campaign to Improve High Level Staff), Brazil, 1953 (Reel L-3)
- 1954
  - L54-8: Book on pre-Columbian music, 1954 (Reel L-3)
  - L54-20: Land problem conference in Iraq, 1954 (Reel L-3)
  - L54-36: Agricultural credit conference in the Near East (V. Webster Johnson), 1954 (Reel L-3)
    Related Materials
    See also L54-1338: Expanding program of agricultural development in Syria as related to assistance from the Ford Foundation.
  - L54-100: Study of the Foreign Service officer, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-145: Improvement to technological education in Great Britain, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-159: Encouragement of private organizations sponsorship of public service activities in the Near East, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-201: Aid to Canadian National Ballet, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-274: Education and research, International Association of Chiefs of Police, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-286: Support for the University of Liberia, Africa, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-500: Program in arts and cultural representation, International Educational Exchange Service, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-543: Support for International Society for Music Education, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-544: Workshops to evaluate various village development approaches, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-551: Review by foreign nationals of United States foreign policy, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-633: American students attending Indian Universities, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-646: 'House of Altars' open for world peace through religion, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-669: Support of academic or technician exchange project, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-733: Support to Urban Land Institute, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-852: Seminars in extension work in overseas countries, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-853: Post-doctoral travelling fellowships for study of extension work throughout the world, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-854: Seminar, Land Grant College extension member to attend overseas colleges, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-855: Seminar for members of Land Grant College team on overseas program, problems, etc., 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-856: College scholarships for service on Land Grant College team in foreign countries working with youth, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-857: Visit of Land Grant College team leader to Near East countries and India, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-877: Bring Burmese and Thai students to United States for study, Mortimer Graves, American Council of Learned Societies (ACLU), 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-879: Employment of older people, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-903: Establishment of Pius XII Memorial Library, St. Louis University, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-905: Support for educational and vocational training in Pakistan, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-908: Vocational education schools in Lebanon, Syria, and the Near East, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-909: Education and vocational training in the Near East, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-910: Public administration training in the Near East, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-911: Economic training in Iraq, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-932: Myasthenia Gravis Foundation Inc., New York Academy of Medicine, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-935: Support for invention encouragement, Southwest Research Institute, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-938: Lectures on American economy and political institutions for Cuba, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-965: World Industrial Economic Development Fair, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-990: Survey of Soviet and East European studies in the American educational system, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1019: Test for aptitude for overseas employment developed by agencies of government, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1051: Aid in making American university press books more available to European scholars, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1053: Atomic Energy Peace Prize, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1058: Support to staff of 'The Echo' for trip to Middle East, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1069: Nursing training pediatric care, St. Augustine Hospital, Amarillo, Texas, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1078: Jordan Valley television program, Near East program, 1954 (Reel L-4)
  - L54-1302: Review of the Foreign Study Fellowship Program, 1954 (Reel L-5)
  - L54-1338: Expanding program of agricultural development in Syria as related to assistance from the Ford Foundation (V. Webster Johnson), 1954 (Reel L-5)
    See also L54-36: Agricultural credit conference in the Near East.
  - L54-1342: Survey of International Student Activities (Carl Spaeth and Werner Warmbrunn), 1954 (Reel L-5)
  - L54-1352: Desegregation survey -- Regional program in the production of behavioral science materials for use in desegregation, 1954 (Reel L-5, Reel L-6)
    See also Ford Foundation grant 05400130 (PA54-130), Cornell University, SUMMARY OF RESEARCH FINDINGS RELATING TO DESEGREGATION.
  - L54-1364: Agricultural machinery for the Near East and Pakistan (C. Leigh Stevens, Agricultural Missions, Inc.), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1377: Study to aid the development of proper grading standards (Educational Testing Service), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1414: Rural development program in Jordan (Rowland Egger), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1475: Development planning in Surinam (W. Alan Laflin, U.S. Operations Mission to Surinam), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1532: Training of Congressional representatives (Lorrin P. Thurston, The Honolulu Advertiser), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1552: Center for Asian Studies (Arno G. Huth, Asian Study Group), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1574: Committee for an American Library in Switzerland, 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1599: Develop a constructive approach to the problem and prevention of juvenile crime (Herbert Mayer, American Viewpoint Inc.), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1601: Program of research an evaluation for the International Information Administration (Wilbur Schramm Committee reports, U.S. Department of State), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1627: League of Nations documents from the Bureau of United Nations Affairs library, U.S. Department of State (Denys P. Myers), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1683: Seminar on community development in India (Carl C. Taylor, U.S. Technical Cooperation Mission to India), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1691: Memorandum for the March 2, 1955 Joint Subcommittee Meeting of Ford Foundation Trustees and the Directors, Fund for Adult Education (FAE), 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1695: Training of graduates of the National Police Academy in the Social Sciences, Indonesia, 1954 (Reel L-6)
  - L54-1711: Support to the National Capital Area Council, Boy Scouts of America, 1954 (Reel L-7)
  - L54-1754: Litani River project, Lebanon (Cedric Seager, U.S. Foreign Operations Administration), 1954 (Reel L-7)
  - L54-1767: Support to Lonesome Pine Council, Boy Scouts of America, 1954 (Reel L-7)
- 1955
  - L55-40: Study of public opinion (Lester Markel, New York Times), 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-84: Nuclear reactor, University of Buffalo, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-90: Humanities Research Center, College of Arts and Sciences, Baghdad, Iraq, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-91: Research program in comparative public administration, American University of Beirut, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-92: Research in international legal studies in Cairo, Egypt and Beirut, Lebanon, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-95: Rural Development Program in Burma, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-98: Economic and social research in in Burma, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-99: Industrial research program in Burma, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-100: Educational and vocational training program in Burma, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-101: Applied Industrial Research and Development Center, Ford Foundation Beirut Field Office, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-130: Orientation training for business and other foreign representatives (Stanton S. Von Grabill, American Institute for Foreign Trade), 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-152: Exchange of cultural mission between India and the United States (Indo-American Cultural organization), 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-160: Proposal for a National Council on Asian Affairs, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-186: Expansion of rural village development work, East Bengal, Pakistan, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-192: Social Science and Humanities program, Islamic College, Lahore, Pakistan, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-193: Social Science and Humanities program, Forman College, Lahore, Pakistan, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-205: International Society for the Welfare of Cripples, 1955 (Reel L-7)
  - L55-263: Survey of atomic energy field (Dean C. Dulavey and David F. Cavers), 1955 (Reel L-7)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes "Government Regulation of Atomic Industry" by Dean C. Dunlavey, 1956.
  - L55-282: Metropolitan Areas program, (Public Affairs program, Ford Foundation), 1955 (Reel L-7, Reel L-8)
    See also Ford Foundation grants to the Regional Plan Association: 05600210 (PA56-210), STUDY OF NEW YORK METROPOLITAN REGION; 06000323 (PA60-323), FOLLOW UP ITS STUDY OF METROPOLITAN NEW YORK AND STRENGTHEN NON-GOVERNMENTAL LEADERSHIP; and 06400234 (PA64-234), PREPARATION OF A COMPREHENSIVE DEVELOPMENT PLAN FOR THE NEW YORK METROPOLITAN REGION.
    Includes the Summer Study Group on Metropolitan Problems, "Report on Metropolitan Problems", October 1955, and the Public Affairs program's "Metropolitan Program, Introductory Memorandum", June 1956.
  - L55-283: Training of lawyers for public affairs, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-306: Teacher training program for secondary school teachers, Canisius College, Buffalo, New York, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-333: Training of American for service in foreign lands, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-338: Expansion of program, International Christian Leadership, Inc., 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-354: Training for responsible partnerships abroad, Overseas Service, England, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-411: Support to the National Council for the Panel of Americans, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-416: Research on New England economy of the Reserve Bank of New England, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-453: Support for science shows and natural history field trips, Scientists of Tomorrow, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-521: Creation of 'Nobel Prize' in fields of peaceful uses of atomic energy, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-547: School in Trinidad, Fundamental Baptist Mission of Trinidad, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-551: Support for conference on foreign policy, travel institute, and monthly publication, Young Adult International Relations Council, Kansas City, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-553: Program of the Oberlin-in-China Memorial Association to establish relationships with a foreign institution of higher learning, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-557: Support to the Institute for Sex Research at Indiana University, Wentworth P. Johnson and Alfred Kinsey, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-576: Study of the need and scope of international schools, International Schools Association, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-594: Vocational training for mentally handicapped children, Cape Cod Association for Retarded Children, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-656: Civic law office, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-659: Folksong Foundation, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-673: Liszt Society, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-674: Research on economic institutions in early society, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-679: Improving the training of journalists, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-683: Problem of marine food resources for underdeveloped areas, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-707: Criminal justice commission of the City of New York, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-756: Assistance for Tacoma Farm High School, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-857: Japanese biography project, 1955 (Reel L-9)
  - L55-858 - 'Operation Love' project to improve race relations (Coleman Leroy Hacker, Second Baptist Church, Springfield, Ohio), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-861 - Georgetown University Law School symposium on section 501(c) of the Internal Revenue Code (Frank Dugan), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-865 - Distribution to colleges and schools of recent film featuring Herbert Hoover in discussion of his ideas and ideals (A.C. Wedemeyer), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-872 - YMCA, establishment of Family Life Institute, new pattern of programming for community life, 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-884 - Reuben G. Gustavson attendence as an observer at the International Conference on Peaceful Uses of Atomic Energy, 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-904 - Committee Advocating the George S. Counts Project re publication of book on Russian education from 1918-1956 (Harry Uviller), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-905 - Syracuse University - Summer Institute on Japan (Douglas G. Haring), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-915 - Proposed program of reearch on the Middle East and Africa (Elizabeth Maund), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-952 - Adelphi College, Five year program for the training of business and industrial executive personnel, 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-964 - Proposal to establish a Center for European-American Intellectual Cooperation, and workshop on the study of the Declaration of Human Rights (George Edward Gordon Catlin), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-1006 - Support to 'Girlhaven' School for Girls (E. Geraldine Mundy), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-988 - Community Council of Springfield, and Clark County, Ohio, 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-1014 - Support to universities to train Soviet university lecturers (Michael J. Flack), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-1017 - Free Nurses Institute, Inc., general support, 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-1019 - Plan for stimulating students in science and engineering (Morton D. Fagen), 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-1035 - Los Angeles County heart Association, general support, 1955 (Reel L-10)
  - L55-1044 - Handy Associates Inc., international relations (Howard G. Kurtz Jr.), 1955 (Reel L-10)
- 1956
  - L56-9 - Dr. Otto Hahn's visit to the United States, as a guest of the Ford Foundation, 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-11 - Support for meeting of the International Association of Legal Science, 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-49 - Travel grant to Herbert F. York (Atomic Scientist), 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-72 - California Traffic Safety Foundation, general support, 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-105 - Contemporary Dancers Foundation, San Francisco, 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-110 - Support for establishment of a 'Museum of Personnel', 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-113 - Private philanthropy in Canada (Floyd S. Chalmers), 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-137 - Support for the School of Oriental Studies, University of Durham, England, 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-148 - Design for Transportation Research in Metropolitan Areas, Northwestern University (Franklin M. Kreml), 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-176 - American Consul General, assistance to education institutions in the Ryukyus islands, Japan (John M. Steeves), 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-184 - Contribution to the scholarship funds of the Cordell Hull Foundation (Thomas D. Blake), 1956 (Reel L-10)
  - L56-185: Staff study on possible activities in the field of atomic energy - Ford Foundation, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-190: support for expansion of operations, New York State Citizens Council, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-210: National Council for Youth, Inc., 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-213: Establishment of a library of American literature, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-214: Support to the Aspen Music Festival and music school, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-226: Research in mental health, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-230: 'Conflict Resolution', a journal for research related to war and peace, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-242: Proposed study of Asia, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-250: Assistance to development planning in Burma, 1956 (Reel L-11)
  - L56-265: Staff study on the physical fitness of American youth - Ford Foundation, 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-277: Support for new building, Magnolia Boy's Town, Laurel, Mississippi, 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-284: Distribution of agricultural research publications in India, and developing countries, Douglas Ensminger and Nobel Clark, 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-306: Nuclear and atomic energy in Indonesia (Michael Harris, Ford Foundation Representative, Indonesia), 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-317: United Nations program of technical assistance in Burma, 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-323: International definition and measurement of standards and levels of living, United Nations Economic and Social Council, 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-325: Two enterprises, Plimouth Plantation, Plymouth, Massachusetts (David L. Patten), 1956 (Reel L-12)
  - L56-333: Organization of Foundation material relevant to past Congressional hearings on tax-exempt foundations, William Greenleaf, Consultant, 1956; Greenleaf, William, 1917-1975 (Reel L-12)
    See also Log Files: L56-1111: History of the Ford family philanthropies which preceded establishment of the Ford Foundation, William Greenleaf, Consultant; L56-1112: "Bibliography of American philanthropy since 1900", William Greenleaf, Consultant; and L57-1209: "History of the Ford Foundation, 1936-1956", William Greenleaf, Consultant.